One thing to note is that each data point here has 34 associated features.
需要注意的一点是 每个数据点都有 34 个关联特征
So this is 34 dimensional data which is pretty high dimensional.
这个 34 维数据是很高维度的数据
Unsupervised algorithms rely on finding relationships in n dimensional feature space.
非监督式算法需要寻找 n 维特征空间里的关系
For higher dimensions, we often get noisier clustering, for example.
对于更高维度 通常会获得噪点更多的聚类
So an algorithm like K-means has
K 均值等算法
a hard time figuring out which dimensions to pay attention to.
很难判断要关注哪些维度
Some of these dimensions are not as important as others.
某些维度不如其他维度重要
For example, if every county in our dataset had the same exact total population,
例如 如果数据集中的每个郡县总人口都一样
then this particular feature wouldn't give us any distinguishing information.
那么这个特征就不能提供有意义的信息
It would not help us to separate the counties into
不能帮助我们将郡县分成不同的组
different groups because its value doesn't vary between counties.
因为它的值在郡县之间没有变化
This is just a hypothetical example.
这只是一种假设
Instead, we really want to find the features that help us separate ungrouped data.
我们希望寻找能帮助区分未分组数据的特征
In other words, we want to find features that cause the most variance in our dataset.
换句话说 我们希望寻找会导致最大的数据集变化的特征
So before we cluster this data with K-means,
在使用 K 均值聚类数据之前
I want to take one more step,
我还要执行一个步骤
a dimensionality reduction step.
即降维步骤
My aim will be to form a smaller set of
目的是创建一个更小的特征集
features that will better help us separate our data.
这些特征可以更好地帮助我区分数据
The technique we'll use is called PCA or Principal Component Analysis.
我们将采用的技巧叫做主成分分析 (PCA)
PCA is most useful when you have a bunch of features and you want
如果数据中有大量特征并且你想知道
to find out which linear combinations of these features matter the most,
哪些特征线性组合最重要 它们可以解释数据集的最大变化
which are responsible for the largest variance in our data.
那么可以使用 PCA
So to perform PCA,
为了执行 PCA
we'll use SageMaker's built-in model for PCA.
我们将使用 SageMaker 的内置 PCA 算法
To create any model,
为了创建任何模型
you'll first need to specify an IAM role and SageMaker session.
首先需要指定 IAM 角色和 SageMaker 会话
Please let the model know what permissions and session to train in.
需要告诉模型使用哪些权限和会话进行训练
So in this cell here, I'm storing our SageMaker session by calling sagemaker.Session.
在这个单元格中 我通过调用 sagemaker.Session 存储 SageMaker 会话
This is a capital S. It's a session object,
这里是大写的 S 它是会话对象
and I'm storing that as a variable here.
将其存储到这个变量中
Then, I am getting the IAM role.
然后获取 IAM 角色
We specified this role earlier,
我们之前指定了该角色
and I'm getting it by name with an import get_execution_role.
通过导入get_execution_role 并按名称获取该角色
I'll actually print it out to make sure it's the right name.
输出该角色 看看名称是否正确
So we have our session, and this role name should
我们创建了会话并且这个角色名称
look familiar from when we created the Notebook.
在之前创建 Notebook 时就设定了
Next, we'll also need a place to store the trained model in an S3 bucket.
接着 还需要将训练的模型存储到 S3 存储桶中
So in this next cell, I'm creating a default bucket from
在下个单元格中 我通过调用 .default_bucket
our SageMaker session with a call to.default_bucket,
从 SageMaker 会话中创建默认的存储桶
and I'm saving the name of that bucket for reference later.
并保存该存储桶的名称以供后面引用
If you print out the name of this default bucket,
如果你输出这个默认存储桶的名称
you should get something like this.
结果应该是类似于这样的名称
It says SageMaker, and then it has your region,
sageMaker 然后是区域
mine is US-West-1, and then some numbers to make it unique.
我的是 us-west-1 最后是一个唯一编号
Then, I'll start to build a PCA model and I'll need to do a few things.
然后开始构建 PCA 模型 需要完成几个步骤
First, I'm going to specify exactly where,
首先 指定要将
in our S3 bucket,
训练过的模型工件
I want to store the trained model artifacts.
存储在 S3 存储桶的哪个位置
I'll specify a prefix for a directory where I want to store the data,
我将指定一个 prefix 表示数据的存储目录
calling it counties for data about counties in the US.
称为 counties 表示美国郡县的数据
Here I'm creating the entire output path which is a string that points to the bucket,
在这里创建整个输出路径 它是一个指向存储桶的字符串
and the prefix directory.
位于 prefix 目录中
Next, it's time to define the PCA model.
接下来定义 PCA 模型
So this model is built-in in SageMaker and I can import it by name, import PCA.
这个模型是一个内置 SageMaker 模型 可以按照名称导入它 输入 import PCA
Then, I'm creating a model down here.
然后在下面创建一个模型
I'm saving it as pca_SM for SageMaker,
保存为 pca_SM SM 表示 SageMaker
and I'm calling our PCA constructor here.
在这里调用 PCA 构造函数
This takes in several arguments.
括号里有多个参数
First, I'm passing in the IAM role which we defined above.
首先 传入在上面定义的 IAM 角色
Then, I'm specifying the train instance count,
然后指定 train_instance_count
which will usually be one,
通常为 1
and the instance type,
以及 train_instance_type
which I'm setting as a c4.xlarge.
设为 ml_c4.xlarge
Then, I'll specify the output path as this one that we defined above.
然后将 output_path 指定为上面定义的路径
Again, this is the place that the resultant model data will be stored in S3.
这个路径表示生成的模型数据在 S3 中的存储位置
Then, I'm also passing in the SageMaker session that we also just defined.
还要传入刚刚定义的 SageMaker 会话
Now, there's one last thing I need to specify,
最后还要指定一项
and that is a hyperparameter for the PCA model.
这是 PCA 模型的超参数
Basically, this model needs to know how many principal components we want to create.
我们需要告诉这个模型我们要创建多少个主成分
We want to reduce our 34 dimensions of data but we'll actually want to first generate
我们希望降低 34 个维度 但是首先需要生成
enough linearly independent principal components to capture the variance in our data,
足够多的线性独立主成分 以捕获数据中的变化
and at later, select the top components to pass to our clustering model.
稍后 选择将前几个成分并传递给聚类模型
So I'll define N_COMPONENTS as 33.
我将 N_COMPONENTS 设为 33
This is the existing feature dimension, 34, minus one.
它等于现有特征维数 34 减一
This is a good rule of thumb for starting PCA analysis.
这是开始 PCA 分析的一项经验法则
So again, I'm going to generate 33 of these principal components, but then, later,
我将创建 33 个主成分
I'll select only a few of the top components to use in our final clustering algorithm.
之后近选择前几个成分并用在最终的聚类算法中
This is going to be in all caps because it's a global variable.
这个全大写 因为它是全局变量
That means after defining it,
所以在定义该变量之后
I'll be able to access it in any later cell in the Notebook.
我将能够在 Notebook 中的任何后续单元格中访问该变量
So let me recap how I create an estimator like this.
总结下我是如何创建这个 estimator 的
First, I'm going to import that built-in model from SageMaker,
首先从 SageMaker 导入该内置模型
and then this takes in a number of constructor parameters.
然后在这里传入几个构造函数参数
It takes in the role and SageMaker session which I got an a cell above, here.
包括角色和在上面的单元格中定义的 SageMaker 会话
They're default parameters that are accessible from our Notebook.
它们是可以从 Notebook 访问的默认参数
The session and role are variables that you can always get from your Notebook instance.
session 和 role 是始终可以从 Notebook 实例中获得的变量.
I also specified an output path which is where
我还指定了一个输出路径
this model will be saved after it trains in our S3 bucket.
表示模型训练后将在 S3 存储桶中存储的位置
Then, I had to specify the instance count and type for training.
接着指定实例数量和训练类型
Lastly, our hyper parameter for a PCA model,
最后指定 PCA 模型的超参数
the number of components,
将我们要生成的成分数量
33, that we want to generate.
设为 33
Okay. So I'm running the cell.
Ok运行该单元格
Then, after defining this model,
定义了该模型后
I'll actually want to create a training job and train it on our county's data.
我需要创建一个训练作业 并在 counties 数据上进行训练
A requirement for all of
所有的
SageMaker's built-in models is that the passed-in training data be a record set.
SageMaker 内置模型都要求传入的训练数据是记录集
This allows training of models within SageMaker to perform really fast compared to,
这样的话 与 Scikit-learn 等模型相比
say, Scikit-learn models, especially for large datasets.
在 SageMaker 中训练模型速度非常快 尤其是对于大型数据集来说
So to get a record set format, first,
为了变成记录集格式
I'm going to convert our scale dataframe into
首先通过调用 values.astype(‘float32’)
a NumPy array calling values.astype, float32.
将缩放范围的 dataframe 变成一个 NumPy 数组
I'll save this NumPy array as train_data_np.
将这个 NumPy 数组保存为 train_data_np
Then, I can actually call our model.record_set and pass in
然后调用模型的 .record_set
this NumPy data to create our formatted training data in a record set format.
并传入这个 NumPy 数组以创建记录集格式的训练数据
So going from NumPy to record set,
从 NumPy 转换成记录集
I get our formatted train data.
我获得了特定格式的训练数据
Finally, to train the model,
最后 为了训练模型
I call pca_SM.fit and pass in this formatted train data.
调用 pca_SM.fit 并传入 formatted_train_data
If I run this cell,
如果运行此单元格
this should kick off a training job and I can see the name of that training job here.
将启动训练作业并在这里看到训练作业的名称
This job will take a little while to complete,
这个作业需要运行一段时间
so I can show you a few things while it runs.
在运行期间 我再演示一些其他功能
I'm actually going to go back to my Amazon SageMaker console.
转到 Amazon SageMaker 控制台
Now, in all these buttons on the side,
在左侧有很多按钮
you'll see this one for training jobs.
这里有个“Training jobs”
When I click this, I can actually see the PCA job that I just kicked off.
点击该按钮可以看到刚刚启动的 PCA 作业
It's in progress. I'll see a list of all these other jobs that I've done in the past.
它处于 InProgress 状态可以看到我之前运行过的这些作业列表
But let's click on this most recent one that's in progress.
我们来看看正在运行的最近这个作业
So in here, I can see the job name and the IAM role that it's attached to.
在此页面可以看到作业名称以及关联的 IAM 角色
I can see that it's in progress and read a bit about the details about this training job.
可以看出它正在运行 看看这个训练作业的详细信息
If I scroll all the way down to Monitor,
一直向下滚动到“Monitor”部分
I'll actually be able to click on the logs,
我们可以点击日志
which will be really useful if I need to debug
日志对于调试训练作业来说非常重要
a training job if it's failed, for example.
例如如果运行失败了
The logs are where any errors and trace back will be recorded.
日志中会记录任何错误和跟踪记录
A failed job has happened to me a few times as I've developed,
在我的开发经历中 我遇到了几次作业失败的情况
and the key is just to read through the logs and debug.
解决方法就是阅读日志并调试
Debugging is part of coding just like any other step.
就像任何其他步骤一样 调试也是编程的一个步骤
So I just wanted to show you this option of how to
我刚刚演示了如何查看
explore more information about a unique training job.
关于唯一训练作业的更多信息
Back to my Notebook, I can also see how
回到 Notebook 我们还可以
the training job is monitored in the Notebook itself.
在 Notebook 本身中监控训练作业
I'll see print statements and timestamps that indicate when an instance is being spun up,
可以看到输出语句和时间戳 表示实例何时启动的
when import data is being downloaded,
导入数据何时下载的
and some details about the training in progress.
以及关于训练作业的进度信息
Then, because I was timing this, at the end,
因为我计时了 所以最后可以向下滚动
I can scroll down and see how long this whole process took a few minutes.
看看整个流程花费多长时间 有几分钟时间
Now that this training job is complete,
训练作业已经运行完毕
I have a trained model.
我已经获得了训练过的模型
Next, I'll actually want to see the principle components that the model has come up with.
接下来 我将查看模型生成的主成分
I want to see what linear combinations of features make up each component and decide on
我要看看组成每个成分的线性组合是什么
the number of top components to include as I
并判断在创建新的降维训练数据时
create new reduced dimensionality training data.
要包含多少个前几个成分